Macbeth Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence Files, 1838-1968, n.d., Series 1:; (Box 1-95, 163-164, OV 165; 96.2 linear feet)
  - Correspondence, 1838-1968, n.d., 1.1:
    - L, Miscellaneous: Luk-Lyb (2605), 1909-1949, n.d. (Box 54)
    - L, Miscellaneous: Lyd-Lyons (2605), 1894-1951 (Box 54)
    - M. H. De Young Memorial Museum (2586), 1932-1947 (Box 54)
    - M. Knoedler & Co., Inc. (NMc57/2604), 1895-1961, (5 folders) (Box 54)
    - M. O'Brien & Son (2614), 1898, 1905-1937, n.d., (5 folders) (Box 54)
    - Mabury, Paul R. (NMc60B/2608), 1914-1926, 1937, (2 folders) (Box 54)
    - Macbeth Farm (see also box 164), 1912-1929, (14 folders) (Box 54)
    - Macbeth Gallery, 50th Anniversary (2608), 1942 (Box 54)
      (congratulatory letters)
    - Macbeth Gallery, 60th Anniversary (2608), 1952 (Box 54)
    - Macbeth Gallery "Smoker," 1923 (Box 54)
    - Macbeth, James, 1914-1919 (Box 54)
    - Macbeth, Jessie L. (Mrs. William) and Phoebe K. Macbeth (Mrs. Robert W.), 1940-1956, (2 folders) (Box 54)
    - Macbeth, Norman, 1917, 1932 (Box 54)
    - Macbeth, Robert William (NMc60B), 1909-1939, (21 folders) (Box 55)
    - Macbeth, Robert William, Letters Regarding Dinner for William Macbeth (NMc60B), 1909 (Box 55)
    - Macbeth, William, 1870-1873, 1892-1916, (2 folders) (Box 55)
    - MacChesney, Clara T. (NMc9/2609), 1897, ca. 1911-1920-1926 (Box 55)
    - MacCormack, W. G., 1923 (Box 55)
    - MacDonald, Alfred, 1927 (Box 55)
    - MacDonald, Helen (Mrs. Ian), 1924-1932 (Box 55)
    - MacDonald, John Dolliver (2609), 1946-1954 (Box 55)
    - MacGilvary, Norwood, 1913-1917 (Box 55)
    - MacGinnis, Henry R. (NMc9), ca. 1906 (Box 55)
    - MacHale, John and William MacHale (2609), 1915-1921 (Box 55)
    - MacKenzie, Alexander C., 1914-1918 (Box 55)
    - MacKnight, Dodge (NMc60B), 1913, 1925-1926 (Box 55)
    - MacLaurin, James D., 1925-1927 (Box 55)
    - MacMonnies, Mary F. (NMc60), 1895-1902 (Box 55)
    - MacNab, Robert B., 1927 (Box 55)
    - MacNeil, Carol Brooks and Hermon Atkins MacNeil (NMc9), 1910-1920 (Box 55)
    - MacNicol, Roy, 1922-1932 (Box 55)
    - Macomber Company, Inc. (2609), 1913-1921 (Box 55)
    - Macomber, Lewis A. (2609), 1894-1911 (Box 55)
    - Macon Art Association (see also Blackshear, Harriet), 1909, 1921-1925, (2 folders) (Box 55)
    - MacPherson, William J. (2609), 1937 (Box 55)
    - MacRae, Elmer L. (NMc9/NMc61/2609), 1901-1917 (Box 55)
    - MacRossie, Allan, Jr., and William MacRossie (2609), 1913-1926, 1932 (Box 55)
    - Macrum, George H., 1913, 1917 (Box 55)
    - Madeira, Clara H., 1925-1927 (Box 55)
    - Madigan, Thomas F. (2609), 1917-1923 (Box 55)
    - Magee, Bernice (Mrs. Franklin R.), 1932 (Box 55)
    - Magill, Beatrice (NMc9), 1897 (Box 55)
    - Magrath, William (NMc9), 1893, ca. 1912 (Box 55)
    - Maguire, Eleanor P. and Richard K. Maguire, 1918-1920 (Box 55)
    - Mahoning Institute of Art (Joseph G. Butler, Jr.; see also Butler Institute of Art; NMc61/2609), 1915-1916 (Box 55)
    - Maitland, Frances, 1913, n.d. (Box 55)
    - Makepeace, Walter D. (2609), 1922-1927 (Box 55)
    - Malcolm, Mrs. Donald, 1925-1926, 1932 (Box 55)
    - Malcolm, Thalia W., 1925-1937 (Box 55)
    - Malden Public Library (2609), 1912-1915, 1922 (Box 55)
    - Malloney, J. Merritt, 1926-1927 (Box 55)
    - Manhattan Storage & Warehouse Co. (2609), 1918-1947 (Box 55)
    - Manley, Thomas R. (NMc9), 1893-1907, 1914-1917 (Box 55)
    - Mann, Parker, 1894, 1918 (Box 55)
    - Mann, Mrs. William J., 1913-1914 (Box 55)
    - Mannow, Elsie M. (2609), 1922 (Box 55)
    - Mansfield, Burton (NMc61/2609), 1899-1932, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 56)
    - Manson, Mrs. George, 1926-1927 (Box 56)
    - Mapes, Charles Halsted (2609), 1913-1924 (Box 56)
    - Marcus, H. Stanley (Neiman-Marcus Company), 1926-1927, 1932 (Box 56)
    - Marcus, Mrs. Herbert, 1925-1926 (Box 56)
    - Marcus, Peter, 1916, 1926-1927 (Box 56)
    - Marechal, Greer (2609), 1946-1950 (Box 56)
    - Maril, Herman, 1946-1953, (3 folders; 1950 includes photographs of Maril's wife and son; 1951 includes catalog of Maril exhibition, 3/27/51-4/14/51;2609) (Box 56)
    - Marion Koogler McNay Art Institute (2609), 1954 (Box 56)
    - Mark, Jacob, 1926-1927 (Box 56)
    - Marks, Arthur Hudson (2609), 1912-1932 (Box 56)
    - Marshall, Clark S. (NMc9), 1907-1912 (Box 56)
    - Marshall Field & Company, 1912-1915, 1932 (Box 56)
    - Marshall, Louis (2609), 1902-1927 (Box 56)
    - Martel, Paul, 1924-1925 (Box 56)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery (2602), 1948-1956 (Box 56)
    - Martin, Elizabeth G. (Mrs. Homer Dodge; NMc9), 1897-1908 (Box 56)
    - Martin, Homer Dodge, Correspondence Regarding, 1897-1908 (Box 56)
    - Martin, J. B. (2609/2610), 1918-1927, 1937 (Box 56)
    - Martin, John, 1919 (Box 56)
    - Martin, Louis I., 1918-1921 (Box 56)
    - Martin, Mary F. (Mrs. William Henry; NMc61/2609), 1913-1927, 1937, 1946), (7 folders) (Box 56)
    - Martin, Ralph (2609), 1903 (Box 56)
    - Martin, Reiford J. (2609), 1942 (Box 56)
    - Martin, Mrs. Wade, 1940-1943 (Box 56)
    - Martin, Willard S. (2610), 1919-1923, 1942 (Box 56)
    - Martinez, Xavier (NMc9/2610), 1905-1924 (Box 56)
    - Martino, Antonio P., 1946 (Box 56)
    - Maryland Institute School of Fine and Applied Arts, 1921-1926 (Box 56)
    - Mase, Carolyn C., 1909-1918, 1932 (Box 56)
    - Mason, John, 1915 (Box 56)
    - Mason, Maud M. (NMc9), 1925-1926 (Box 56)
    - Mason, Roy M., 1923-1932, 1937, (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - Mather, Frank Jewett, Jr. (2610), 1937, 1948-1949 (Box 56)
    - Mathes, Aenid V. and Mrs. K. B. Mathes, 1924-1927 (Box 56)
    - Mathews, Mrs. A. C. (2610), 1916 (Box 56)
    - Mathews, Catharine Van C., 1940-1941, n.d. (Box 56)
    - Mathews, William (2610), 1899-1907 (Box 56)
    - Mattatuck Historical Society (2610), 1913-1917, 1947-1948 (Box 56)
    - Mattern, Karl (2610), 1946-1949 (Box 56)
    - Matthews, N. M. (NMc62/2610), 1898-1925 (Box 56)
    - Maury, Cornelia F. (NMc9), 1894-1906, 1919 (Box 56)
    - Mauve, Lire (NMc9), 1896-1905, (includes letter with pencil sketch, 1/12/02) (Box 56)
    - May, Florence Laud (NMc9), 1911-1914 (Box 56)
    - May, George, 1937, 1957-1958 (Box 56)
    - Mayer, Charles and Jane Mayer, 1947-1948, 1954, n.d. (Box 56)
    - Mayer, Louis (NMc9), 1910-1914 (Box 56)
    - Maynard, Edwin T., 1918-1926, 1932 (Box 56)
    - Maynard, George Willoughby (NMc9), 1893, 1916, 1923 (Box 56)
    - Maynard, Ross H., 1913-1918, 1926 (Box 56)
    - Mazzanovich, Ann and Lawrence Mazzanovich (NMc9/2610), 1912-1927 (Box 56)
    - McArthur Library Association, 1952-1953 (Box 56)
    - McBride, Henry (see also Sun; NMc9/NMc60A), 1901-1951 (Box 56)
    - McBride, Lucia (Mrs. Malcolm L.) and Malcolm R. McBride (2609), 1947-1951 (Box 56)
    - McBrine, John W. (2609), 1913-1926, 1932 (Box 56)
    - McCabe, Lida Rose, 1919-1921 (Box 56)
    - McCaig, Flora T. (NMc9), 1896, ca.1902, 1914-1915 (Box 56)
    - McCarter, Thomas N., 1932 (Box 56)
    - McCarthy, J. F. (2609), 1911, 1916 (Box 56)
    - McCarthy, Thomas F. (2609), 1906, 1920 (Box 56)
    - McCauley, John and Mrs. McCauley, 1914-1925 (Box 56)
    - McCausland, Elizabeth, 1945 (Box 56)
    - McChesney, Clara (NMc9), 1892-ca. 1904, 1917, 1919, n.d. (Box 56)
    - McClees Galleries (NMc60A/2609), 1916-1952 (Box 56)
    - McClellan, Edwin, 1915-1916 (Box 56)
    - McClellan, Jessy T., 1914 (Box 56)
    - McClellan, P. W., 1914 (Box 56)
    - McClintic, Mrs. J. Hunter, 1932 (Box 56)
    - McClintock, Gilbert S. (2609), 1913-1927 (Box 56)
    - McComas, Francis (NMc9/NMc60A/2609), 1902-1926 (Box 56)
    - McCool, J. W., 1932 (Box 56)
    - McCord, Alice Lovett (Mrs. George H.; NMc9/NMc60A), 1895-1913 (Box 56)
    - McCord, George H. (NMc9), 1892-1910 (Box 56)
    - McCorkle, Mrs. W. P., 1926 (Box 56)
    - McCormick, Cyrus H. (NMc60A/2609), 1916-1926 (Box 56)
    - McCormick, Eleanor W., 1927 (Box 57)
    - McCormick, William B. (NMc60A), 1914-1937 (Box 57)
    - McCoy, John W., II, 1950 (Box 57)
    - McCoy, Margaret, 1895, 1914-1920, n.d. (Box 57)
    - McCrea, S. Harkness (NMc9), 1901-1910 (Box 57)
    - McCready, William M., 1899-1907 (Box 57)
    - McCutcheon, George Barr (NMc60A/2609), 1913-1926 (Box 57)
    - McDonald, Agnes J., 1927 (Box 57)
    - McDonnell, J. W., 1949-1956 (Box 57)
    - McDonough, C. J. and Mary L. McDonough (McDonough Art Gallery), 1913-1932, n.d. (Box 57)
    - McEldowney, H. C., 1927 (Box 57)
    - McElory, Anna, 1917 (Box 57)
    - McGregor, Marion K. (Mrs. Charles A.), 1918-1919 (Box 57)
    - McGurk, Jonce I., 1914 (Box 57)
    - McHenry, Charles Morgan, 1893-1901, n.d. (Box 57)
    - McHugh, Mrs. John (2609), 1922, 1927 (Box 57)
    - McIntyre, Florence M.: see Memphis Art Association (NMc60A) (Box 57)
    - McIntyre, Robert G. (NMc60A/2609), 1889, 1909-1962, n.d., (5 folders; see also Series 6: Reference Files) (Box 57)
    - McKenzie, R. Tait, 1911, 1932, 1937 (Box 57)
    - McKinney, Aileen Ford and John L. McKinney (2609), 1912-1919, 1943 (Box 57)
    - McKinney, E., 1916-1925 (Box 57)
    - McKinney, Glenn Ford, 1915-1932 (Box 57)
    - McLean, George, 1926 (Box 57)
    - McLoughlin & McLoughlin, 1927 (Box 57)
    - McManamy, Robert J. (2609), 1916-1924 (Box 57)
    - McMillin, Emerson (2609), 1903-1922 (Box 57)
    - McMurtrie, Douglas C. (NMc60A), 1916-1919 (Box 57)
    - McNeir, George (2609), 1916-1927 (Box 57)
    - McNulty, William C., 1932 (Box 57)
    - McRae, Frances, 1917, 1927, 1932, n.d. (Box 57)
    - McVitty, Albert Elliott (2609), 1917-1926, 1943, (2 folders) (Box 57)
    - Mead, Constance S. (2610), ca. 1893-1903 (Box 57)
    - Meadows, Clarence W. (2610), 1947-1950 (Box 57)
    - Meadville Art Association, ca. 1910, 1914 (Box 57)
    - Meagher, George A., 1919-1924 (Box 57)
    - Mechlin, Leila (2610), 1937, 1941 (Box 57)
    - Medwid, Irene Mary, 1948 (Box 57)
    - Meech, Sylvia Spencer Merrell (2610), 1916 (Box 57)
    - Meeds, Ellen duPont, 1917, 1925, 1932-1937 (Box 57)
    - Meeker, Arthur and Mrs. Meeker (NMc62/2610), 1918-1932 (Box 57)
    - Meeks, Everett W. (National War Work Council), 1918-1919 (Box 57)
    - Meigs, Mrs. Herman, 1918 (Box 57)
    - Meinhard Galleries (2610), 1919-1946 (Box 57)
    - Melchers, Gari (NMc62/2610), 1914-1932, n.d. (Box 57)
    - Melius, Katherine A. and Norman Melius, 1915-1918, 1927 (Box 57)
    - Mellors Fine Arts Limited (2610), 1937 (Box 57)
    - Meltzer, Arthur (NMc62), 1925-1946 (Box 57)
    - Melville, Ward (NMc62), 1914-1915, 1927 (Box 57)
    - Memphis Art Association (Florence M. McIntyre; NMc60A/2610), 1914-1932, 1946, (2 folders) (Box 57)
    - Mente, Charles (NMc9), 1900 (Box 57)
    - Mentor, 1913-1926 (Box 57)
    - Merchants Association of New York, 1932 (Box 57)
    - Merck, George W. (2610), 1948-1950 (Box 57)
    - Merkel, Bernard R. (2610), 1947 (Box 57)
    - Merriam, E. W., 1919 (Box 57)
    - Merrill, Mrs. A. P., 1923-1924 (Box 57)
    - Merrill, E. A., 1915 (Box 57)
    - Merriman, Daniel and Helen B. Merriman (2610), 1898-1923 (Box 57)
    - Merritt, Anna Lea (NMc9), 1898-1903, 1911-1912 (Box 57)
    - Merritt Co., 1915 (Box 57)
    - Merrit, Schuyler and Mrs. Merritt, 1914-1917 (Box 57)
    - Merrymount Press, 1918 (Box 57)
    - Mershon, Edward C., 1915 (Box 57)
    - Messer, Edmund Clarence (NMc9), 1893-1899 (Box 57)
    - Messervy, Essie L. (2610), 1937, 1952 (Box 57)
    - Metal Hose & Tubing Co., 1926-1927 (Box 57)
    - Metcalf, Elizabeth P. and Thomas N. Metcalf (2610), 1937-1947, (2 folders) (Box 57)
    - Metcalf, Houghton P., 1924-1927 (Box 57)
    - Metcalf, L. B. (Mrs. F. A.), 1915-1919 (Box 57)
    - Metcalf, Willard L. (NMc9/NMc62/2610), 1906, 1913-ca. 1924, n.d. (Box 57)
    - Metcalfe, N. W. (NMc9), 1894-ca. 1898 (Box 57)
    - Meteor Press (2610), 1909-1920 (Box 57)
    - Metropolitan, 1913-1914 (Box 57)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art (NMc62/2610), 1895-1955, (4 folders) (Box 57)
    - Meyer, A. B. (2610), 1906, 1916 (Box 57)
    - Meyer, Annie Nathan (2610), ca. 1905-1937 (Box 57)
    - Meyer, Felicia (Mrs. Reginald Marsh), 1943-1949, n.d. (Box 58)
    - Meyer, Herbert (2610), 1926-1937, 1946-1951, (2 folders) (Box 58)
    - Meyer, Sallie G. (Mrs. George K, Dallas Art Association), 1923-1932, (3 folders) (Box 58)
    - Meyerowitz, William (NMc62), 1932 (Box 58)
    - Michaelson, Cornelius, 1931-1932 (Box 58)
    - Michener, Louis T., 1925 (Box 58)
    - Middleton, Stanley (NMc9), 1892, 1900-ca. 1901, n.d. (Box 58)
    - Midtown Galleries (2610), 1946-1950 (Box 58)
    - Mieloz, Charles, 1898 (Box 58)
    - Mielziner, Leo (NMc62), 1914, 1925-1926 (Box 58)
    - Mikkelsen, Gwendolen H. (NMc9), ca. 1910, 1916 (Box 58)
    - Milch Galleries (NMc63/2610), 1912-1959, (4 folders) (Box 58)
    - Miles, William Sonntag (2610), 1950, 1960 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Annie, 1912 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Bernard P., 1916-1918 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Celena W. (Mrs. W. D.), 1924-1927 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Mrs. Charles E., 1927, 1932 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Charles Henry (NMc9), 1898, 1900, 1913 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Mrs. Charles W. (Morristown Civic Club), 1925-1926 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Elmer C., 1925-1926, 1932 (Box 58)
    - Miller, George P. and Laura Chapman Miller, 1914-1916, 1925 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Helen P. (NMc9), 1911 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Henry and Estate (NMc63/2610), 1903-1924, (3 folders) (Box 58)
    - Miller, Henry, Estate, Lena Miller and Vera Miller, 1925-1943, n.d. (Box 58)
    - Miller, Hester, 1915-1920, n.d. (Box 58)
    - Miller, Kenneth Hayes (NMc9/NMc62/NMc63/2610-2611), 1910-1923, 1946 (Box 58)
    - Miller, L. B., 1921 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Lee (NMc9), n.d. (Box 58)
    - Miller, May, 1913-1914 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Oscar (NMc9), 1899, 1906, 1913-1915 (Box 58)
    - Miller, R. L. (2611), 1911-1914 (Box 58)
    - Miller, Richard E. (NMc9/2611), 1911-1926, 1932, (3 folders) (Box 58)
    - Miller, Mrs. William D., 1913 (Box 58)
    - Millet, Lily (Mrs. Frank D.; NMc63), 1926-1927 (Box 58)
    - Millet, Stephen C. and Mrs. Millett, 1915-1920 (Box 58)
    - Milhoff, Mary K. (Mrs. C. B.; 2611), 1943-1944 (Box 58)
    - Milliken, Arthur N. (2611), 1909, 1915, 1932, 1937 (Box 58)
    - Mills, H. A. (NMc9), 1894 (Box 58)
    - Mills, Lyman A., 1900-1909 (Box 58)
    - Milwaukee Art Institute (2611), 1919-1932, 1947-1950, (3 folders) (Box 58)
    - Milwaukee Art Society, 1910-1916 (Box 58)
    - Miner, Lawrence W. (NMc9), 1892-1899 (Box 58)
    - Miner, Lilian B., 1925 (Box 58)
    - Mink, Edward W., 1932 (Box 58)
    - Minneapolis Institute of Arts (NMc63/2611), 1914-1926, 1932, (2 folders) (Box 58)
    - Minneapolis Tribune, 1914, 1921 (Box 58)
    - Minnesota State Art Commission/State Fair (2611), 1915-1917, 1923, 1947 (Box 58)
    - Minor, Anne Rogers (Mrs. George M.; 2611), 1917-1920 (Box 58)
    - Minor, Robert C. (NMc9/NMc63), 1892-1900 (Box 58)
    - Minshall, Helen, 1911-1915 (Box 58)
    - Misson, E. C. (NMc9), 1900 (Box 58)
    - Mitchell, Alfred R., 1923-1926 (Box 58)
    - Mitchell, Belle and Julian Mitchell (2611), 1913-1927, 1940-1950, (3 folders) (Box 58)
    - Mitchell, H. Walton (2611), 1916-1927, 1932, (2 folders) (Box 58)
    - Mitchell, Lucy Sprague and Wesley C. Mitchell (NMc63/2611), 1913-1927, 1937, 1953 (Box 58)
    - Mitchell, Virginia L., 1917 (Box 58)
    - Mitcheson, Robert S. J. (NMc63/2611), 1916-1927 (Box 59)
    - Mix, George H., 1909-1910 (Box 59)
    - Mix, James E., 1926-1927 (Box 59)
    - Mixter, Florence K. (Mrs. George W.), 1927, 1947 (Box 59)
    - Moes, Wally (NMc9), 1898-1901 (Box 59)
    - Mohr Art Galleries, 1919, 1927-1932 (Box 59)
    - Mohun, Nora M. (Mrs. Barry; 2611), 1937-1946 (Box 59)
    - Molarsky, A., 1915, 1918 (Box 59)
    - Molarsky, Morris and Mrs. Molarsky, 1915, 1918 (Box 59)
    - Moncrieff, Sue, 1917 (Box 59)
    - Monsarrat, Corinne B. (2611), ca. 1910-1912 (Box 59)
    - Mont, Betty, 1947 (Box 59)
    - Montague, Estelle V. Z. (2611), 1913-1919 (Box 59)
    - Montague, Lilian A. (NMc9), 1905 (Box 59)
    - Montana State University, 1937 (Box 59)
    - Montclair Art Museum (NMc64/2611), 1916-1963, (5 folders) (Box 59)
    - Montgomery, Alice Howland (Mrs. Hugh E.; 2611), 1937 (Box 59)
    - Montross Gallery (N. E. Montross; NMc64), 1913-1925, 1932 (Box 59)
    - Moon, Carl, 1923 (Box 59)
    - Moore, A. E. (Mrs. H. M.), 1923-1924 (Box 59)
    - Moore, Annie Caroll, 1917-1924 (Box 59)
    - Moore, Mrs. Barrington (NMc64), 1924-1925 (Box 59)
    - Moore, Dorothea (Mrs. E. C.; 2611), 1913-1932, n.d. (Box 59)
    - Moore, Edwin N., 1925, 1937 (Box 59)
    - Moore, James B., 1918 (Box 59)
    - Moore, Junius T. (2611), 1945-1950 (Box 59)
    - Moore, Neil A. and Vera J. Moore (2611), 1946-1948 (Box 59)
    - Moore, Mrs. R. T., 1927 (Box 59)
    - Mora, F. Luis (NMc9/NMc64/2611), 1908-1932 (Box 59)
    - Mora, Louis F. J. (NMc9/2611), 1919-1925 (Box 59)
    - Moran, Thomas Sidney (NMc9), 1905 (Box 59)
    - More, Isabelle S. (Mrs. E. W., Southeastern Fair Association), 1919-1920 (Box 59)
    - Morey, Florence (Mrs. Charles Henry), 1926-1927 (Box 59)
    - Morey, Samuel F. (2611), 1899-1925 (Box 59)
    - Morgan, Antoinette C. (Mrs. John), 1923-1927 (Box 59)
    - Morgan, Charles H. (2611), 1954-1959 (Box 59)
    - Morgan, Georgie, 1914, 1921 (Box 59)
    - Morgan, John Hill (2611), 1910-1944, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 59)
    - Morgan, M. DeNeale, 1926 (Box 59)
    - Morgan, W. Forbes (2611), 1915-1917 (Box 59)
    - Morley, Albert Healey, 1916-1925 (Box 59)
    - Morning Telegraph, 1923-1926 (Box 59)
    - Morrey, J. B., 1921 (Box 59)
    - Morris, Catharine Wharton and Harrison S. Morris (2611), 1898-1927, 1946, (2 folders) (Box 59)
      (includes 4/5/46 letter describing memories of Albert P. Ryder and visits to his studio)
    - Morris, Lewis (Margaret Stiles, Agent; 2611), 1922-1923 (Box 59)
    - Morris, Mrs. Lewis R., 1927 (Box 59)
    - Morrison, Hal (NMc9), 1892-1895 (Box 59)
    - Morrison, Richard (2611), 1949-1956 (Box 59)
    - Morristown Topics (2611), 1921-1927 (Box 59)
    - Morrow, Julie (Mrs. De Forest), 1917-1922, 1932 (Box 59)
    - Morse, Edna (2611), 1942-1943 (Box 59)
    - Morse, Edward L. (2611), 1922 (Box 59)
    - Morse, Leila Livingston (2611-2612), 1914, 1922-1951 (Box 59)
    - Morse, Walter C. B. (2612), 1940-1956 (Box 59)
    - Morten, Alexander and Marjory Morten, 1908-1917 (Box 59)
    - Morton, Benjamin A. and Mrs. Morton, 1924-1926 (Box 59)
    - Morton, Bliss & Co., 1894 (Box 59)
    - Morton, Charles I. (2612), 1937 (Box 59)
    - Morton, F. W. (2612), 1905-1906 (Box 59)
    - Moschcovitz, Paul (NMc9), 1906, 1927 (Box 59)
    - Moser, James Henry (NMc9), 1903-1911 (Box 59)
    - Moses, Shirley M., 1932 (Box 59)
    - Mosher, Mrs. Edward (2612), 1941 (Box 59)
    - Mosle, A. Henry and Mrs. Mosle, 1917, 1923 (Box 59)
    - Moss, Florence D., 1927, n.d. (Box 59)
    - Moss, Frank (NMc9), ca. 1899 (Box 59)
    - Motch, Stanley, 1927 (Box 59)
    - Mott, C. S. (NMc64), 1914-1915 (Box 59)
    - Mott, W. C., 1920-1925 (Box 59)
    - Mottet, Jeanie Gallup (Mrs. Henry; 2612), 1916-1918 (Box 59)
    - Moulton and Ricketts, 1909-1913 (Box 59)
    - Mount Holyoke College (2612), 1927-1958 (Box 59)
    - Mowbray-Clarke, Mary H. (Mrs. John Frederick; NMc9), 1909 (Box 59)
    - Moyer Gallery (Curtis H. Moyer; 2612), 1916-1943 (Box 59)
    - Muhrman, Henry (NMc9), 1895-1899 (Box 59)
    - Mulford, Allen, 1930 (Box 59)
    - Mulhaupt, Frederick J., 1917-1932 (Box 59)
    - Mulvane Art Museum (Washburn College), 1927-1932 (Box 59)
    - Mulvany, John (NMc9), 1903-ca. 1904 (Box 59)
    - Mumford, Alice, 1899-1911 (Box 59)
    - Mummert, Sallie Blyth (2612), 1925-1937, (2 folders) (Box 59)
    - Munger, Fay W. and Roy Munger, 1923-1927 (Box 59)
    - Munger, Gertrude and Stephen Munger, 1924-1937 (Box 59)
    - Munger, H. M. and Mrs. Munger, 1923-1926, 1932 (Box 59)
    - Munn, Charles A. (NMc64), 1915-1919 (Box 59)
    - Munson Williams Proctor Institute (2612), 1948-1957 (Box 59)
    - Murdock, J. Edgar, 1925-1926 (Box 60)
    - Murdock, Louise (Mrs. Roland P.; NMc64), 1912, 1915 (Box 60)
    - Murdock, Louise C. (Estate, Elizabeth S. Navas, Trustee; see also Wichita Art Association; 2612), 1956-1957 (Box 60)
    - Murphy, Adah C. (Mrs. J. Francis; NMc9), ca. 1892-ca. 1912 (Box 60)
    - Murphy, Deacon (2612), 1921-1925, 1932 (Box 60)
    - Murphy, Franklin and Harriet Murphy, 1925-1927, n.d. (Box 60)
    - Murphy, Henry O., Jr., 1912 (Box 60)
    - Murphy, Hermann Dudley (NMc9/2612), ca. 1899-1937, n.d., (4 folders) (Box 60)
    - Murphy, John Francis (NMc9/NMc65), 1892-1919, (5 folders; illustrated letter 8/24/96) (Box 60)
    - Murphy, Larry, 1926 (Box 60)
    - Murray, Alec, 1914-1917 (Box 60)
    - Murray, Charlotte, 1926-1927 (Box 60)
    - Murray, Ottie M., 1932 (Box 60)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1895-1953, 1962, (7 folders) (Box 60)
    - Museum of Fine Arts of Houston, 1952-1953 (Box 60)
    - Museum of Modern Art (NMc65/2612), 1930-1953, (2 folders) (Box 60)
    - Museum of the City of New York (2612), 1932-1946 (Box 60)
    - Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York, 1898-1954 (Box 60)
    - Myers, Ethel and Jerome Myers (NMc9/NMc65/2612), ca. 1903-1945 (Box 60)
    - Mygatt, Robertson K. and Mrs. Mygatt (2612), 1916-1923 (Box 60)
    - Mystic Art Association, 1917-1937 (Box 60)
    - M, Illegible, 1900-1949 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Maas-MacD (2607-2608), 1893-1953 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: MacH-MacN (2607-2608), 1892-1958 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Maco-Mai (2607-2608), 1903-1963 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mal-Man (2607-2608), 1906-1953 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Map-Marsh (2607-2608), 1896-1954 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Marshak-Martin, H. (2607-2608), 1893-1951 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Martin, J.-Mass (2607-2608), 1895-1955 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mast-Mau (2607-2608), 1906-1951 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Max-May (2607-2608), 1909-1951 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: McA-McCh (2607-2608), 1900-1959 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: McCl-McCu (2607-2608), 1896-1954 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: McE-McI (2607-2608), 1900-1953 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: McK-McM (2607-2608), 1896-1950 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: McN-McV (2607-2608), 1896-1957 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mea-Mel (2607-2608), 1894-1956 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mem-Merm (2607-2608), 1903-1953 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Merr-Mey (2607-2608), 1895-1949 (Box 60)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mic-Millen (2607-2608), 1903-1962 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Miller (2607-2608), 1895-1951 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Milles-Min (2607-2608), 1896-1951 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mir-Miz (2607-2608), 1898-1951 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mod-Monc (2607-2608), 1896-1956 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mong-Mont (2607-2608), 1896-1951 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Moo (2607-2608), 1898-1952 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Moran-Morgan (2607-2608), 1907-1948 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mori-Mott (2607-2608), 1868-1954 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mue-Mung (2607-2608), 1904-1949 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Muni-Mur, 1896-1956 (Box 61)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mus-My (2607-2608), 1899-1961 (Box 61)
    - N. A. Berwin & Co., Inc., 1932-1942 (Box 61)
    - N. W. Halsey & Co., 1913-1915 (Box 61)
    - Nachman, Joe (NMc66), 1929, 1932 (Box 61)
    - Naegele, Charles Frederick, 1895, 1924-1925 (Box 61)
    - Nagler, Fred (NMc66), 1926, 1932 (Box 61)
    - Nagy, Stephen K., 1916, 1923-1924 (Box 61)
    - Nail, R. E., 1927-1930 (Box 61)
    - Nakamizo, Fugi, 1929-1930 (Box 61)
    - Nash, Howard (2612), 1937 (Box 61)
    - Nash, P. Bredt, 1913 (Box 61)
    - Nashville Trust Company, 1924-1925 (Box 61)
    - Nason, Thomas W., 1930-1937, n.d. (Box 61)
    - National Academy of Design (NMc66/2612), 1895-1952, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 61)
    - National Arts Club (NMc66/2612), 1899-1932, 1946-1951, n.d. (Box 61)